Lesson 38 Water and the traveller
38  水和旅行者
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
What does this text describe?
本文叙述了什么?
sanitation: n.  卫生，卫生设备
Contamination of water supplies is usually due to poor sanitation close to water sources,
水源的污染通常是由于接近水源的地方卫生条件太差而造成的:
sewage: n.  污水, leakage: n.  泄漏
sewage disposal into the sources themselves leakage of sewage into distribution systems,
污水排入水源,污水渗入给水系统,aa
or contamination with industrial or farm waste.
或工农业污水造成污染.
Even if a piped water supply is safe at its source,
既使管道供水系统在水源处是安全的,
it is not always safe by the time it reaches the tap.
等水到达龙头时就不一定总是安全的了.
Intermittent tap water supplies should be regarded as particularly suspect.
断断续续的水管应该被视为是非常可疑的.
Travellers on short trips to areas with water supplies of uncertain quality
短途旅行到水质不保险的地区时,
should avoid drinking tap water,or untreated water from any other source.
应避免饮用水龙头的水或未经处理任何其他来源的水.
It is best to keep to hot drinks,bottled or canned drinks of well-known brand names,
最好仅饮用开水,名牌瓶装或罐装水,
international standard of water treatment are usually followed at bottling plants.
装瓶厂通常遵循国际水处理的标准.
Carbonated drinks are acidic,and slightly safer.
碳酸饮料是酸性的,就更安全一些.aa
Make sure that all bottles are opened in your presence,
确保瓶子是当着你的面开启的,
and that their rims are clean and dry.
而且瓶口清洁干燥.
Boiling is always a good way of treating water.
烧开一直是水处理的一种好办法.
Some hotels supply boiled water on request
有的酒店根据要求可提供开水,
and this can be used for drinking,or for brushing teeth.
这些开水可用于饮用和刷牙.
Portable boiling elements that can boil small quantities of water are useful
如果条件允许,可以煮少量水的便携式热水装置是有用的,
when the right voltage of electricity is available.
这个条件就是有相配的电压.
Refuse politely any cold drink from an unknown source.
应谢绝任何不明来源的冷饮.
Ice is only as safe as the water from which it is made,
冰块只有当制造冰块的水安全时才是保险的,
and should not be put in drinks unless it is known to be safe.
只有知道冰块安全时才能加入饮料.
Drinks can be cooled by placing them on ice rather than adding ice to them.
可以把饮料置于冰块之上来冷却,而不是把冰块加进饮料之中.
disinfectant: n.  消毒剂
Alcohol may be a medical disinfectant,
酒精可能是医学上的消毒剂,
sterilize: v.  消毒
but should not be relied upon to sterilize water.
但决不可用来消毒饮用水.
Ethanol is more effective at a concentration of 50-70 per cent;
乙醇的浓度为50%至70%时比较有效,
below 20 per cent,its bactericidal action is negligible.
浓度低于20%时,杀菌能力基本上就不存在了.
alcohol: n.  酒精
Spirits labelled 95 proof contain only about 47 per cent alcohol.
强度标为95的酒中含47%的酒精.
alcohol: n.  酒精
Beware of methylated alcohol,
要提防甲基化酒精,
which is very poisonous and should never be added to drinking water.
那是剧毒的,永远不能掺入饮用水.aa
If no other safe water supply can be obtained
如果没有其他安全的饮用水,
tap water that is too hot to touch can be left to cool
水管中流出的烫手的水可以留下来冷却,
and is generally safe to drink.
这种水一般是安全的.
Those planning a trip to remote areas,
那些计划去偏远地区旅行,
or intending to live in countries where drinking water is not readily available,
或在饮用水不现成的国家居住的人,
should know about the various possible methods for making water safe.
应该知道如何使水适于饮用的各种办法.